{
    "id": "3733477812dd41bb9df237a3114d6a70",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The meeting will start at six o’clock ……………………..",
            "description": "As an adverb sharp can mean punctually.",
            "answers": [
                "sharp",
                "sharply",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You shouldn’t have spoken to her rather ……………………….",
            "description": "Sharp can mean punctually as an adverb. Sharply is used to express other meanings.",
            "answers": [
                "sharp",
                "sharply"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Under no circumstances ………………………. allowed in the pub.",
            "description": "After negative adverbial expressions like ‘under no circumstances’ we use an inverted word order. That means the auxiliary goes before the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "kids are",
                "are kids"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He launched his own business after ………………………. from the US.",
            "description": "After + ing often has the same meaning as after + having + past participle.",
            "answers": [
                "returning",
                "having returned",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ……………………… as her husband.",
            "description": "No preposition is used in the structure ‘be + … age’.",
            "answers": [
                "the same age",
                "at the same age",
                "of the same age"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………….. a few minutes ago.",
            "description": "We cannot normally use the present perfect tense with ago.",
            "answers": [
                "arrived",
                "has arrived",
                "had arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. was there.",
            "description": "Hardly anybody means the same as almost nobody. Nearly is not normally used before negative expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "Hardly anybody",
                "Hardly nobody",
                "Almost nobody",
                "Nearly nobody"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "They were quarreling all ………………………… the journey.",
            "description": "We prefer through to talk about periods or activities. ",
            "answers": [
                "over",
                "along",
                "through"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You could go by train, or ……………………….. you could hire a taxi.",
            "description": "Alternatively means instead.",
            "answers": [
                "alternately",
                "alternative",
                "alternatively"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We have been living ……………………… this street for ten years.",
            "description": "On is used in American English and in is used in British English.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "on",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You look ……………………. with a beard.",
            "description": "Look is a copular verb. We use an adjective, not an adverb to modify copular verbs.",
            "answers": [
                "different",
                "differently",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Why don’t you do something for ………………………….?",
            "description": "Others can mean other people.",
            "answers": [
                "other people",
                "others",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}